Jo Faircloth BEng(hons) DIS CertWAD(open) MIET

Miss Jo Faircloth, 20 The Pines, Haywards Heath, West Sussex RH16 3TX 01444 453673 · 0779 296 2680 | jo@jofaircloth.co.uk · http://jofaircloth.co.uk

A graduate of electronic engineering with seven years experience of complete ASP.NET and database design cycles (from spec to deployment, front- to back-end). I continue to learn, and have an Open University qualification in Web Applications Development. » I am looking for an opportunity to be involved in dynamic web application projects, where I can gain new, and improve, my skills.

Skills Outline

- ASP.NET (VB, C#, Framework 3.5, Visual Studio 2008)
- MSSQL (including T-SQL, design, triggers, permissions, installation)
- XSL-FO: for dynamic PDF generation from XML
- Creation of AJAX controls
- (X)HTML, CSS, Javascript, XML

- Classic ASP (VBScript)
- Requirements gathering and functional specification writing, upto business sign off
- Use of 3rd party tools to generate code and documentation from the database
- Academic/home experience in PHP, MySQL, Java, WPF

Work Experience

Analyst Developer

May 2008

February 2011

Alico (AIG Life)/MetLife, Invicta House, Trafalgar Place, Brighton, BN1 4FR

- Worked on a large ASP.NET (VB) 3.5 web application.
- Had additional responsibility for one component, from functional specification and sign off to managing database changes, test data, business objects, front-end, and test methods.
- Wrote necessary helper methods and AJAX. Used/developed using generics, interfaces, LINQ/JSON. Developed most CSS/HTML for the site. Used 3rd party tools (OpenAccess, CodeSmith) to script and generate data access classes and documentation for the database.

Web/Applications Developer

Excel Aviation/XL Leisure Group, Explorer House, Fleming Way, Crawley, RH10 9EA

- Designed the group intranet with MSSQL backend and ASP.NET (C#) business objects and front end. Used MS Office API to interface with MSExcel and MSWord.
- February 2004 April 2008
- Researched use of Microsoft Office SharePoint Server 2007 for an updated intranet and communications portal. Built a secured Windows Server 2003 server and client PC (Windows XP) for testing and development.
- Built bespoke web and Windows applications; from consultation, design and development, to testing, integration into the business, and support.
- Project managed a 3rd party document management project, for integration into multiple systems within the business.
- Provided user support for a number of 3rd party and in-house systems.

Junior Engineer

Trimble Navigation New Zealand Ltd Birmingham Drive, Christchurch, New Zealand

February 2003 August 2003

- Worked as part of an international development team, developing a 'Rugged Colour Display Unit'. Researched, designed, implemented and documented a parts database system and symbols library.
- Worked individually whilst communicating with engineers in New Zealand and the USA, to ascertain company expectations and international standards for the system.
- Organised meetings and presented results regularly.
- Designed a digital board to customer, mechanical, system and cost specifications gaining an insight into specification writing, discussing and implementing.

Supermarket Assistant April - Nov 2002

Waitrose, 10 Sayers Lane, Tenterden, TN30 6BN

- Worked service counters and grocery area.
- Made sure paperwork was completed and helped train new recruits.

Diploma in Industrial Studies

Tandberg Television, Stoneham Lane, Eastleigh SO50 9NW

 Assisted in the complete design of a successful demodulator (a cutting-edge digital broadcasting), from schematic to testing, on a DVB-T, OFDM project.

Junior Engineer

- Wrote VHDL for a Virtex FPGA, C for simulations and analysed MPEG Transport Streams.
- Learned and used the schematic design package, Mentor.

July 1999 –July 2000

· Communicated between small teams, to learn and achieve targets.

Housekeeper Summer 1998

Bayshore Inn, Waterton Lakes National Park, Alberta, Canada

Worked a 6-day week in a housekeeping team in a busy Canadian resort hotel.

Education

2004 - 2011

The Open University

CertWAD(open)

A qualification, studied in my own time, to support my career aims.

Relevant technologies and skills gained, include:

PHP
 MySQL and database design
 Web Standards
 Time management, prioritisation
 Network architecture

Part time study courses:

TT280 (Web basics: design, development and management) - HTML/CSS

TT281 (The client-side of application development) - Javascript TT282 (The server-side of application development) – ASP TT380 (Databases within website design) - CFML

TT381 (Open source development tools) – PHP/MySQL TT382 (Web server management, performance and tuning)

Personal interest courses

T396 (Artificial Intelligence for Technology)

S282 (Astronomy)

S283 (Planetary Science and the Search for Life) [in progress]

SXR208 (Observing the Universe) [in progress]

1997 – 2001 BEng(hons) DIS Loughborough University, Leicestershire LE11 3TU

Electronic and Electrical Engineering, with Diploma in Industrial Studies

Modules studied include:

Communication/Computer Networks
Computer Peripheral Systems
Digital Data Transmission Systems
Java/Internet Programming
Software Engineering
Programming in C++

Fibre Optics Microwave/Optical Transmission FPGAs/VHDL Personal Radio Communications

Industry and Business RF Systems

Class obtained: Second class with Honours and a Diploma in Industrial Studies (DIS).

Final year project

"Force feedback control of a remote vehicle over an RF modem".

A user application for Windows, using self-studied Visual C++, DirectX and the MFC, to handle

serial data from a hardware sensor.

A levels

Cranbrook (Grammar) School, Kent. Mathematics, Physics, Economics.

Positions of Responsibility and Interests

Church Bell-ringing

- I ring 3-4 times a week, and for Sunday services. As a more advanced member at many towers, I often explain complicated concepts to beginners.
- I am the Steeple-keeper at St Swithun's, East Grinstead and sit on the East Grinstead and District Guild committee.

Steam Locomotive Overhauling • I work at Sheffield Park, Bluebell Railway, on a steam locomotive once a week (a Maunsell S15) - giving me the opportunity to work on very practical projects and with a varied group of people. I am a company director of the Maunsell Locomotive Society.

******* Working abroad

- I worked long hours to afford a work and travel holiday in New Zealand, financed by securing a career related job abroad.
- I also self-funded a 3 month trip to Canada, by getting a job whilst there.

Complementary Skills

- I am computer literate able to write integral web and Windows applications, and design/develop databases. I can
 provide basic support for client PCs and servers (at application and operating system level). I have an
 understanding of network architectures and requirements for security.
- o I am a very cheerful and bubbly person and get on well with others. My previous experience in working abroad shows I like to be independent, committed to achieving my goals and keen to work with and learn from others.
- o I am a member of the IET (Institute of Engineering and Technology), formerly IEE.
- o I have a full clean UK driving licence.

References

References available on request.